

Richard Weston

Principal Cloud Systems Developer

Phone: +44 7738 276 354 **Email:** mail@riweston.io

LinkedIn: /in/riweston GitHub: /riweston

A Principal Cloud Systems Developer with over 10 years of experience in the IT industry. I have a strong background in developing and maintaining cloud-native applications, and I am passionate about cloud computing, DevOps culture and platform engineering. I am a strong advocate for automation and quality engineering practices, and as a technical leader, supporting and mentoring teams so that we all grow together.

Skills

I already know

Azure 4	1/5	Google Cloud		4/5	Terraform		5/5	Gith	itHub Actions		5/5		Bash	4/5
Go 3/5		TypeScri	pt 2/5	Ру	thon	3/5	Kuber	netes	4/5	Flu	ıx 3	/5		
Promethe	eus	2/5	Grafana	2/5										

I want to learn

Nix CUE Cilium Data Pipelines

I speak

English Native

Work Experience

Principal Cloud Systems Developer

February 2020 - now

Cloudreach

- Leading a team of 10 engineers to deliver a cloud-native platform for a major UK bank.
- Designing and implementing a Kubernetes-based platform on Azure.
- Developing and maintaining cloud-native applications.
- Mentoring and supporting team members.
- Leading the adoption of best practices and quality engineering.
- Working with stakeholders to understand requirements and deliver solutions.
- Supporting the sales team in pre-sales activities.

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process.

Working with the marketing team to create content.

Technologies: AKS, Azure, Google Cloud, GKE, Go, Python, Terraform

Infrastructure Engineer (Cloud & Automation)

April 2018 - October 2018

TFL

- Built CI/CD pipelines and process to build IaC environments using Azure DevOps.
- Cost analysis and cloud resource consolidation using cloud governance and compliance tooling.
- Developed Azure native automation tools using DSC/Runbooks/Managed Service Catalogues

Technologies: Azure, Azure DevOps, PowerShell

Windows Systems Administrator

March 2015 - April 2018

Rackspace

- Managed public cloud hosted on Openstack platform.
- Dedicated private cloud support on VMware hosted infrastructure.
- Enterprise support for Windows Server.
- · Health monitoring with SCOM and New Relic.
- Developed high quality Powershell functions for large scale execution across Rackspace managed services.

Technologies: Active Directory, PowerShell, VMware, Windows Server

Education

BSc Computer Games Design

October 2006 - July 2010

Staffordshire University

Master degree. Specialization in computer games design.